好了  各位  蛋糕时间
Okay, everybody. Cake time!
老天  我真的得去学习
Thank god. I really have to study.
亲爱的  你就不能抽出点时间享用吗
Oh, sweetheart, can't you just take a minute to enjoy it?
这可是你的生日啊
It's your birthday.
你给自己施加太多压力了
You put too much pressure on yourself.
我还记得我16岁那年
I remember my sweet 16.
我想要个主题派对
I wanted a theme party.
《月色撩人》刚刚上映  但我还没出柜
"Moonstruck" had just come out, but I hadn't, so --
别讲故事  没时间听
No stories, no time --
我是要考大学入学考试的人啊
S.A.T.s.
来吧  各位
Here we go, everybody.
等等  等等
Wait, wait.
我们都知道在庆祝什么
We all know why we're here.
-亲爱的  你落下了一根  -我知道
- Ay, honey, you missed one. - I know!
我知道我落下了一根  我不是傻子
I know I missed one! I'm not an idiot!
这样  开心了吧
There! Happy?!
-你有点...  -失控是吗
- You're being a little... - Obstreperous?!
顽抗  还是野蛮
Recalcitrant?! Truculent?!
我本来想说"神经兮兮"
I was gonna say "Cray-cray."
艾丽克斯  亲爱的
Alex, sweet...
我真的得集中精神
I really need to focus!
有个16岁的科学天才
There is a 16-year-old science prodigy
在约翰・霍普金斯大学做癌症研究
studying cancer research at Johns Hopkins!
16岁  瞧瞧我在干什么
16! What am I doing?!
我在吃蛋糕
I'm eating cake!
别这样  别这样
No, no, no.
蛋糕  蛋糕  蛋糕
Cake! Cake! Cake!
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：小饭  流苏  小花豆  王大可  四方虾  丁小七
时间轴：浓子  加森   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第十二集
艾丽克斯在昨晚过后  可能会有点脆弱
Alex might be a little bit fragile after last night,
所以我们得小心对待她
so let's try to be sensitive.
相信我  从现在起
Oh, believe me -- I am going to be
我都会对她耐心又友好
nothing but nice to Alex from now on.
如果她哪天突然崩溃  实施暴行
If she snaps and goes on a rampage,
你觉得她会最先找上谁
who do you think she's coming for first?
她不会实施暴行的
She's not going on a rampage.
我赌她会留我一命  她喜欢我
I bet she'd let me live. She likes me.
坦白说  我从不信任她
I'm just gonna say it -- I never trusted her.
大家都正常一点就行了
Oh, everybody just be normal.
我们要像平时那样对她
We're gonna treat her exactly the way we usually do.
她来了
And there she is.
-美女  -你睡得怎么样
- Hi, pretty girl. - How'd you sleep?
-不错  -你的头发看起来超柔软  小艾
- Fine. - Your hair looks super-soft, Al.
那是新的毛衣吗  超爱
And is that a great new sweater? Love!
老爸  你能把黄油刀递给我吗
Dad, can you hand me the butter knife?
不行
No!
海莉  卢克  请上楼去
Haley, Luke, upstairs, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
好吧  谈谈我昨晚的失控
So, about my meltdown.
-谁  -什么失控
- Who? - What meltdown?
我想去看心理医生  我查了一下
I want to see a therapist. I did some research.
格雷戈里・克拉克医生  超高推荐度
Dr. Gregory Clark -- highly recommended,
专治青少年  在我们的医保范围内
specializes in teenagers, and is covered by our insurance.
我预约了今天找他看两个钟
I booked a double session with him today.
既然你们今天要参加学校开放日
And since you guys have the open house,
我自己坐公交去
I will be taking the bus.
-好  -听起来不错
- Okay. - That sounds good.
她简直像个自动清洁炉
She's like a self-cleaning oven.
快看看
Check it out.
我今天要以复古造型亮相开放日
I'm rockin' the old school for the open house today.
我要为体育课重新注入活力
I'm gonna put the "Fizz" back in "Phys Ed."
[小卡的艺名是"Fizzbo"菲茨宝]
我喜欢  全都喜欢
I love it -- all of it.
-真的吗  -当然
- Really? - Yeah.
因为我今天想给家长们留下个好印象
Because I want to make a good impression today.
我想成为所有家长谈论的对象
I want to be the teacher all the parents are talking about.
是啊  难怪穿这袜子
Well, that explains the socks.
什么
What?
学校里有一种等级制度
There's a caste system at school --
学术教师在顶层  体育教师在底层
Academic teachers at the top, gym teachers at the bottom.
真的很讨厌  也很无礼
It's offensive and disrespectful.
他们像对待服务员一样对待我们
They treat us like we're lunch ladies.
你好啊  邻居
Hey, there, neighbor.
-是亚瑟  对吧  -没错
- It's Asher, right? - Yeah.
我就是想告诉你
Um, I just wanted to let you know --
我觉得你们家的空调
I think there might be something
-可能坏了  -是吗
- wrong with your air conditioner. - Oh, really?
是啊  好像总是开着
Yeah, I mean, it just seems to be running a lot,
即便屋外还挺凉快的
even when it's, uh, kind of cool outside.
不是  不是
No, no.
我家那位有点怕热
Um, my partner runs a little hot.
那也没我们这个地球热
Not as hot as our planet.
抱歉  我没想那么刻薄
Sorry. I don't mean to be that guy.
只是  我们都在一个星球上
It's just, um, we're all in this together.
是啊  我开的是普锐斯车  所以
Yeah, I drive a Prius, so...
这倒是个不错的态度
And that's a nice little gesture.
我的车用的是回收的食用油
My car runs on reclaimed cooking oil.
我有一些相关文章  可以借你看
I have some literature, if you want it.
不用了  省纸吧
That's okay. Save the paper.
我从2004年起就没有印过任何东西
I haven't printed anything since 2004.
我打算发电邮给你
I was gonna e-mail you.
用你那高耗电的电脑吗
On your power-hungry computer?
我整座房子都是用太阳能供电的
My entire house is solar-powered.
我把电卖回给电网
I sell energy back to the grid
然后用那笔钱救北极熊
and use that money to save polar bears.
我是个环保律师
I'm an environmental lawyer,
所以我也是非常环保[绿色]的
so, you know, I'm pretty green.
你的草地也是嘛
So is your lawn.
我的庭院是抗干旱的
I went drought-tolerant --
多肉植物  本地植物  岩石庭院
Succulents, indigenous plants, rock garden.
我另一个爸爸说你的庭院像猫砂箱
My other daddy says your yard looks like a litter box.
她真是个可爱的孩子
She's a cute kid.
我还记得她穿一次性尿布时的样子
I remember when she was in disposable diapers.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
好了
Yeah.
你穿这么漂亮干嘛  跟我不搭啊
Why do you look like that when I look like this?
我朋友说那是因为你有钱
My friends say it's because of your money.
不  我是说  不过是个学校开放日
No, I'm just saying why is she all dressed up
干嘛盛装打扮
for a school open house?
我想给曼尼的历史老师留下深刻印象
I want to impress Manny's history teacher.
我想让曼尼去华盛顿
I want Manny to go to Washington, D.C.
是的  参加青少年国会
Yeah, Junior Congress.
整个年级只有一个名额
Only one kid in the whole grade gets picked to go.
我觉得我能有所作为
I think I can make a difference.
得了吧  真的国会都只是个摆设而已
Regular Congress can't even make a difference.
别担心  曼尼  包在我身上
Don't worry, Manny. I have it covered.
你只管去好好约会吧
You just go and enjoy your date.
我确实有个约会  没什么大不了
I have a date. It's no big deal.
你不要大惊小怪
D-don't make a whole thing about it.
我的车钥匙哪儿去了
What did I do with my car keys?
我们还只是朋友而已
I mean, we're just friends now,
但我有很好的预感
but I have a good feeling.
好吧  我知道不应该言之过早
I know -- don't get ahead of myself.
每次一放下都找不着了
Every time I put them down.
她叫什么名字
What is her name?
要么是佐伊  要么就是派珀
Either Zoe or Piper.
你怎么连约会对象的名字都不知道呢
How can you be going on a date and you don't know her name?
这就是有意思的地方啊
This is where it gets interesting.
我深表怀疑
I seriously doubt that.
几天前我们差点因为一个女孩争风吃醋
A few days ago, we almost let a girl come between us.
-那是谁  -新来的姑娘
- Who is she? - The new girl.
-好漂亮  -美极了
- She's pretty. - Super-pretty.
我要了
Dibs.
什么  不  你不能这样
What?! N-no. You can't call dibs.
她是个有情感的大活人
She's a human being with feelings,
这不是在抢前排座位
not the front seat.
接着奇迹发生了
Then a miracle happened.
双胞胎  一样的美丽动人
Twins -- each as pretty as the other.
这很有趣  因为卢克和我一般
It's funny -- Luke and I don't usually
不会看上同一类型的女孩
go for the same kind of girl.
没错  我喜欢的类型是"容易上手型"
Yeah. I like to describe my type as "Gettable".
你在干什么  塔克
What are you doing, Tucker?
你好啊  布朗校长
Oh, hey, Principal Brown.
你知道其他的老师总是给家长
Do you know how other teachers drone on and on
讲那些枯燥无趣的老生常谈
to parents with their boring lectures?
我觉得我可以另辟蹊径
Well, I thought I would go another way.
听上去可不大妙
Oh. Well, I don't like the sound of that at all.
你一定会喜欢的
I think you will.
我打算来一堂躲避球课  活跃一下气氛
I'm gonna spice things up with a spirited game of dodgeball.
不要  千万不要  一百个不要
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
在你说"不要"之前
Okay, before you say "No"...
我已经说了"不要"了
I already said "No."
先看看我的全套构思
...let me show you my whole bit.
你们好  伙计们
Howdy, folks.
我名字叫塔克
My name's Tucker.
是"多比"镇警官  其实是"躲避"球
I'm the Sheriff of Dodge...ball.
家长们会哄堂大笑
"Laugh, laugh, laugh."
然后
And then --
不  没有然后  不行
No, no "then." No.
你看到那些家长的身材了吗
Have you seen the shape some of these folks are in?
我们可不想某个家长当场倒毙
We don't need a parent dropping dead in here.
这里是海豚湾体育馆
Look, this is the "Dolphin Den."
可没打算改名叫
I am not renaming it
曼德尔鲍姆纪念馆
the Harvey K. Mandelbaum memorial gym.
但我本来想把大家分成哈特菲尔德队
But I was gonna divide everybody up into
[电影《血仇》中的死对头]
和麦考伊队打比赛呢
the Hatfield and McCoys.
不许打躲避球
Just no dodgeball.
你好  英格拉姆老师
Hello, Mr. Ingram.
我是歌洛莉亚・德尔加多・迪尔加多
I am Gloria Delgado-Pritchett,
曼尼的妈妈
Manny's mother.
没错  当然了
Yes, of course.
我想好好感谢您
I just wanted to thank you so much.
我儿子对您评价极高
He thinks the world of you.
作为移民的小孩
You know, as a child of an immigrant,
您让他对世界有别具一格的新鲜看法
he can look at the world with such a fresh perspective.
提到"新鲜"
And talking about fresh,
我给你带了些墨西哥酥皮饺子
I brought you some empanadas.
真有一套啊
Subtle.
菲尔  克莱尔呢
Hey, Phil. Where's Claire?
她去艾丽克斯的教室了
Oh, she's going to Alex's classes.
我负责卢克这一边
I'm doing Luke's.
你居然来了我很惊讶
I'm surprised to see you here.
你的球队不是今天比赛吗
Isn't your team playing today?
就是啊  但歌洛莉亚非要我来
Yeah. Gloria made me come.
我设好了录像机
I think I'm recording the game,
但谁知道会发生什么意外情况
but, you know, you can never know.
上次我录了六小时的Bravo电视台的节目
The last time, I got six hours of Bravo.
万事皆有可能
And who knows?
保不准曼尼就是第一个拉丁裔总统呢
Maybe Manny's going to be the first Latino President.
你好  英格拉姆老师
Hello, Mr. Ingram.
我是唐娜・邓肯医生
Dr. Donna Duncan,
韦斯利的妈妈
Wesley's mom.
一点小谢礼  不成敬意
Just brought you a little thank-you
因为您是我儿子最喜欢的老师
for being his absolute favorite teacher ever.
-这些蛋糕够白的  -谢谢夸奖
- Those cupcakes are so white. - Thank you.
我是唐娜・邓肯医生
Dr. Donna Duncan.
我是歌洛莉亚
I'm Gloria.
我们见过几次
We've met several times.
当然记得了
Oh, of course.
马里奥的妈妈
Mario's mom.
是曼尼
Manny.
他适应得怎么样  比以前好些吗
And how is he fitting in now? Better?
总之
Anyway...
我带了好东西
Here she is.
你带了个酒壶来学校开放日吗
You brought a flask to an open house?
想来点吗  苏格兰威士忌
You want some? It's Scotch.
不  拿远点
No. Put it away.
别这么娘娘腔
Don't be such a goody-goody.
尝一口  这酒比你年纪还大
Taste it. It's older than you are.
-我才不想喝威士忌  -那就闻一下
- I don't want any scotch. - Well, just smell it.
-好  -邓菲先生  你拿的是酒壶吗
- Fine. - Mr. Dunphy, is that a flask?
不是  是  实际上
No. It is. It I--
我只是  是他的
Uh, I was -- it's his.
才不是我的
No, it's not.
提醒一下  严禁带酒来学校
For the record, no alcohol is allowed on school premises.
你太不象话了  菲尔
For god's sake, Phil,
这才下午两点而已
it's 2:00 in the afternoon.
艾丽克斯  跟我说说你为什么来这里
So, Alex, tell me why you're here.
我昨晚有点情绪失控
I had a little meltdown last night,
我害怕以后还会这样
and I'm afraid it'll happen again.
但下次没准会发生在大学入学考试过程中
But, this time, in the middle of the S.A.T or something.
那你为什么失控了呢
Why do you think you melted down?
我压力山大啊
I'm stressed.
我已经高三了
It's my junior year.
我觉得可能是
Part of me feels like
我的大脑边缘系统有点儿失灵
the limbic system in my brain's a bit off.
有这么一种病  对吧  我做过调研
That's a thing, right? I did some research.
你知道就算你自我诊断了
You know I charge the same
我也照旧收钱  对吧
even if you diagnose yourself?
我只想提高下效率
I'm just trying to move this along.
我还有很多事要做
I have a lot to do.
治疗是讲究过程的
Well, uh, this is a process.
需要花些时间
You know, it takes some time.
你在想什么
What -- what are you thinking?
-没什么  -没事  直说好了
- Nothing. - No, no. Go ahead. Tell me.
我觉得你可能帮不上我
That maybe you're not up for this.
无意冒犯
I mean, no offense.
只不过你看起来比网站上老很多
You're just a lot older than you look on your website.
你上学那个年代有大学入学考试
Did you even have S.A.T.s when you were in high school
或是亚裔学生吗
or Asian kids?
那倒没有
Oh, no. no, no, no.
但也有其他事情让我很担心
But there were other things I worried about --
比如西班牙宗教法庭
Spanish inquisition,
出海寻找世界尽头
sailing off the edge of the world,
还要学习火到底是什么东西
learning how to understand fire.
抱歉
Sorry.
-不如我们换一种方式  -什么
- You mind if we try something? - What?
就当帮我的忙了
Just do me a favor.
深吸一口气
Take a deep breath.
很好
Great.
此时此刻  你在想什么
Now... what's on your mind?
我才想起来在离家之前
Well... I just remembered that I forgot
我忘了给电脑充上电了
to charge my computer before I left
而且我该在周一前买新的索引卡
and that I have to get new index cards before Monday.
希望还有蓝色的
Hopefully they don't run out of the blue ones,
因为不知为何蓝色的能帮助我学习
because, for some reason, those help me study better.
也许是因为它们读起来容易些
Maybe it's because they're easier to read
也许是因为我的药方不管用了
or maybe my prescription's getting worse.
我或许该去找我的眼科医生检查一下
I should probably make an appointment with the eye doctor.
还有  我这个暑假是不是该找个工作
Also, should I get a job this summer
实习经验会不会有利于我的申请
or would an internship look better on my application?
再有  希拉里到底是怎么了
And what is up with Hillary?
她到底要不要竞选
Is she going to run or not?
我觉得她应该完全理解
I mean, I feel like she'd totally understand
被别人风头压在下面的感觉
the feeling of being overwhelmed,
但同时又觉得她没有尽最大努力
but also like you're not doing enough at the same time.
你好  妮娜  你家桑杰怎么样
Hey, Nina, how's Sanjay?
很好  谢谢关心
Oh, great. Thanks.
他在准备入学考试和大学测验
He's just dealing with the S.A.T.s and the A.C.T.s.
还有那个荣誉奖学金申请
And that merit scholarship application
每个人都在努力争取
everyone's so stressed about.
什么  什么申请
What -- what application?
我们从物理考试开始说起吧
Let's begin by talking about the A.P. Physics test,
你们都知道  这门考试安排在
which, as you know, takes place on...
5月21日
May 21st.
卢克和海莉自理能力差
With Luke and Haley,
所以我要为他们安排好所有事
I'm on top of everything because they aren't.
但是艾丽克斯是那么的自立
But Alex is so self-sufficient,
我就撒手让她自己干了[调到自动巡航模式]
I just sort of put it in cruise control.
我在方向盘那儿睡着了
I've fallen asleep at the wheel,
结果现在我的小天才往自己身上抹蛋糕
and now my little genius is covered in cake.
下面是我推荐学生
Now, a list of practice tests I recommend
在考试前做的习题
the students take before then
3a  4c  12a一直到f题
3a, 4c, 12a through "f,"
18d  19a  23c
18d, 19a, 23c,
24g  25h  26a
24g, 25h, 26a...
同时  像鲍勃・迪伦这样伟大的艺术家
Meanwhile, a great artist like Bob Dylan
会在第一轮就出局
would get voted off in the first round, which --
如果你把吸管的一端弄湿
If you wet the end,
就会粘在他脸上
it will stick to his face.
你真是个天才
You're a genius.
派珀  那样做太无礼了
Piper, that's rude.
曼尼  我们合唱队会唱
You know, Manny, in chorus,
《随风飘荡》这首歌
we sing "Blowin' in the wind."
这才叫做"随风飘荡"
Now that's blowin' in the wind.
你真风趣  卢克
You're funny, Luke.
曼尼和我要去趟洗手间
Manny and I need to use the restroom.
是吗
We do?
你得跟我换换对象
You've got to switch with me.
什么  不行  我们不能那样做
What? No, we can't do that.
她们是双胞胎  是不会发觉的
They're twins. They'll never notice.
你知道我们俩不是双胞胎吧
You realize we're not twins, right?
莉莉的娃娃屋特快专递来啦
Special dollhouse delivery for Lily!
来啦  来啦
It's here, it's here!
你绝对会爱上它的
I think you're going to love it.
我像你这么大的时候  整天都在玩这个
I spent so many hours playing with this when I was your age.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
快点把车熄火
Hey, quick, turn off your car.
怎么了  在停车模式上呢  我觉得
Why? It's in park, I think.
我有个邻居是环保人士
I have a judgey green neighbor.
他竟然有胆子跑过来
He had the nerve to come over here
跟我说我不够环保
and tell me that I'm not green enough.
不会吧  你超级环保的
Shut up! You're super-green.
谢了  我回收利用了个娃娃屋
Thank you. I'm -- I'm recycling a dollhouse.
我甚至还"回收利用"了个孩子
I even recycled a child.
-你不是还赢了个奖吗  -对的对的
- Didn't you win some award? - Yes, yes.
州律师协会奖  为了表彰在环境法方面
The state bar association award for sustained excellence
做出长期卓越的贡
in the field of environmental...
对对对  就是这个
yeah, yeah, yeah. That's the one.
献  还有一个字没说完呢
...law. There was one word left.
你没有必要打断我
You didn't have to cut me off.
先把娃娃屋拿出来再说
Dollhouse, please.
好的  马上就好
Okay. Yeah, in a minute.
你知道该怎么做吗
You know what you should do?
去他家找他
March right over there
向他炫耀一下你的奖杯
and wave that trophy in his stupid eco face.
不是吧  你真这么想吗
No. You think?
没错  这些人烦死了
Yes. Those people are so annoying.
我们学校有个女生
There's this girl at my school
一直指责我说我的靴子是皮的
who was all over me about my boots 'cause they're leather.
可她自己还穿"鳄鱼牌"[洞洞鞋]
Meanwhile, she's wearing Crocs,
好像那就没有濒临灭绝一样
like those aren't endangered.
你知道么  我就要那么做
You know what? I am gonna do that.
让他知道我有多环保
Show him to out-green me.
-好吧  不  -不
- Okay. Oh, no. - Oh, no.
都吹到他的院子里了
All right, those are blowing into his yard.
这  这绝对对我不利
That is -- okay, that's definitely gonna hurt my case.
你把这些捡起来
Uh, you pick these up.
我去拿奖杯  莉莉  你帮她捡
I'm gonna go get the trophy. Lily, help her.
我听到你说"回收小孩"的话了
I heard that "recycled child" comment.
多谢你的酒瓶
Thanks to your little flask,
现在老师认为我是个酒鬼
now the teacher thinks I'm a burnout.
橄榄球赛
Football game.
Football game!
-你在干吗  -现在可以语音搜索了
- What are you doing? - You can do this now.
我在广告上看到的
I saw it in a commercial.
那款手机做不到
Not with that phone.
跟对着钱包说效果一样
You might as well say it into your wallet.
快点  我们要赶不上数学课了
Come on. We're gonna be late for math.
我不会再去那些无聊的课了
I'm not going to any more boring classes.
你要半途而废吗
You're just gonna cut?
不  不去上课是因为我已经六十多了
No,I'm just not gonna go because I'm in my 60s.
教师休息室
Teacher's lounge.
这里有台电视机
They got a TV in here.
-我们不能去教师休息室  -为什么不
- We can't go in the teacher's lounge. - Why not?
-因为那是老师专用的  -你就是老师
- Um, it's for teachers only. - You're a teacher.
你现在就在教我怎么做个小怨妇
Right now, you're teaching me how to be a little bitch.
杰  不要  杰
Jay, don't. Jay.
杰
Jay!
您大概什么时候做决定呢
So, when do you think you'll be making your decision?
下周左右吧
Oh, sometime in the next week or so.
慢慢来  逼您做决定是不礼貌的
Oh, take your time. It would be rude to rush you.
在别人谈话的时候插嘴
Not as rude as interrupting two people
更没礼貌
in the middle of a conversation.
实际上我得走了
Well, actually, I'll go.
我要喝点咖啡
I'm gonna go grab some coffee.
就是  那些蛋糕看起来就很干
Good idea because those cupcakes look very dry.
这简直让人难以置信
Okay. This is unbelievable.
他们刚给了我四本关于申请名校的书
They just gave me four books on applying to top colleges.
我哪来的时间读完这些
When am I gonna have time to read all this?
天啊  真对不起
Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry.
我没看到你  快来吧  各位
I didn't see you there. Come on, girls.
她超过分的
Oh, she's so mean.
-怎么可能有人注意不到我  -她是谁
- Everybody sees me. - Who was that?
多达・达达医生
Dr. Dooda Dada.
她以为可以靠色诱老师帮她儿子去华盛顿
She thinks that she can flirt her son all the way to Washington,
我不会让她得逞的
but I'm gonna take her down.
我很想跟你聊  可我得去微积分课
I would love to chat, but I got to get to A.P. Calc.
体育课是学校生活的重要部分
Physical education is a critical part of every school day.
我们学习知识的同时  也应该锻炼身体
As we develop the mind, so we must the body.
首先需要保证营养  勤做运动
This begins with good nutrition, uh, physical activity,
培养体育精神以及注重个人卫生
sportsmanship, and attention to personal hygiene.
不  拜托你们不要走
No, please, please, please don't go.
我知道这很无聊  可这不是我安排的
I know this is boring, but this isn't my idea.
我本来想组织一场躲避球大赛  可是
I wanted to play a spirited game of dodgeball, but --
听起来很有趣  我要玩躲避球
That sounds fun. I'll play dodgeball.
我也要玩
I'll play, too.
任何东西都比讲这些有意思
Anything's got to be better than this.
知道吗
Oh, well, you know what?
我们真的不应该那么做  可是知道吗
We're really not supposed to, but you know what?
各位  听着  我叫小卡
Hey, guys, listen to this. My name's Cam.
是"多比"镇警官  其实是"躲避"球
I'm the sheriff of Dodge...ball.
你们是哈特菲尔德队
Okay, you guys are the Hatfields.
你们是麦考伊队
You are the McCoys.
曼德尔鲍姆先生  请您继续坐着
Mr. Mandelbaum, I'd like you to stay seated.
您来做我们的裁判就好
You're gonna be our referee.
好了  各位  躲避球大赛开始
All right, everybody, let's dodgeball!
躲避球比赛精彩极了
Dodgeball was a smash.
唐娜医生和歌洛莉亚像两个刺客
Dr. Donna and Gloria were like two assassins
把他们的目标一个一个干掉
just picking off their victims one by one.
终极躲避球对决
Okay, last two dodgeballers.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
准备好了
Yes.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
准备好了
Yes!
不好意思
Oh, I'm so sorry.
我要杀了你
I'm going to kill you!
歌洛莉亚  歌洛莉亚不要激动
Gloria, Gloria, Gloria, don't!
我的眼睛  你们怎么能这样
Ow! My eye! I don't understand you!
你喜欢戏剧
So, you like theater,
而你刚在薯条里放了根假拇指
and you just put this fake thumb in our fries.
没错
Yep.
这么说也许有点冒险
I'm gonna go out on a limb here
可是我们也许约错人了
and say we're with the wrong people.
我们互换对象就解决问题了
Let's just switch dates and get this party started.
什么  我们不想换
What? We don't want to switch.
我对你没兴趣
Yeah. I'm not attracted to you.
我也对你没兴趣
And I'm not attracted to you.
等等
Wait a minute.
我们爱好相同但你却不喜欢我吗
We like all the same things, but you don't think I'm cute?
我对拉丁裔男生有好感
I've got a thing for Latin men.
我喜欢呆一点的
I like 'em dumb.
-这很伤人  -而且肤浅
- Ugh. Well, that's just offensive. - And shallow.
我们是男生不代表我们不会受伤
Just because we're guys doesn't mean we don't have feelings.
我觉得这不太好
Yeah. I don't feel good about this.
让我觉得
It makes me feel...
很糟
bad.
算了  卢克  我们走吧
Come on, Luke. Let's get out of here.
我们的父母不在家
Our parents aren't home.
如果你们愿意  我们可以和你们亲热下
If you want, we'll make out with you.
接下来发生的事我并不引以为豪
I'm not proud of what happened next.
我觉得很好
I am.
他不在家
He's not home.
你打扫得怎样了
How's the cleanup going?
我觉得大部分搞定了
Well, I think I got most of them.
你搞了这么久
You've been at this a while.
怎么只捡了八个塑料球呢
How come you only have like eight peanuts?
我只是没有把它们抱着到处走
Instead of carrying them around,
我把它们都堆在那里
I made a huge pile right over th--
-又来  -天哪  到处都是
- Again?! - Geez. They're everywhere.
天哪  不  有只鸟
Oh, god. No! Bird!
不要啊
Aah! Oh, no!
不  不  不  不
Oh, no! No, no, no, no, no!
不  这是什么味道
Oh, no! What is that smell?!
闻起来像炸薯条
It smells like french fries!
这是生物柴油  你能把它塞起来吗
It's biodiesel. Can you plug it up?
-用什么塞  爆米花吗  -天哪
- Oh, what? With what? Popcorn? - Oh, geez. Oh, god.
不  我的靴子  真是场灾难
No! My boots! This is a disaster!
保护海豹
Save the seals!
什么  什么情况
What -- what -- what -- what the hell?
你们做了什么
What did you do?
我赢过一座环保奖杯
Uh, I won a green award.
就是这样
That's what.
你确定你能修好这东西吗
You think you can get this thing to work?
你应该去放哨的
Hey, you're supposed to be the lookout.
有人进来了怎么办
What if somebody walks in?
他们会打给我父母
Gee, they'll call my parents.
看  你成功了
Hey! Look! You did it!
是啊  不是很复杂
Yeah, it's not that big of a deal.
听着  我要回课堂了
Listen, I'm gonna get back to class.
你走之前  我有个问题想问你
Before you go, let me ask you a question.
你怎么会这么擅长修理东西呢
How do you know how to do all this stuff?
高中时  我是影音俱乐部的
Back in high school, I was in the A.V. Club.
我们做过很多疯狂的事情
We did all kinds of crazy things.
有一年  我们在体育馆藏了一台麦克风
One year, we hid a microphone in the gym.
毕业舞会发生的事情我们都能听到
We could totally hear everything that was going on at prom.
我曾经取笑过你们这种人
I used to make fun of guys like you.
但这很酷
This is pretty cool.
真的吗
Really?
你觉得这就算酷了
You think this is cool...
第一次进攻  好样的
First down! All right.
史上最棒的学校开放日
Best open house ever.
在影音俱乐部里一切都轻而易举
It's all gravy when you're in the A.V.
承认吧  打破些规则
Admit it -- doesn't it feel good
游走在制度边缘
to break a few rules,
是不是感觉挺好
take a walk on the wild side?
-不用谢  -不  是你不用谢
- You're welcome. - No, you're welcome.
这些都是我搞的
I'm the one who set this whole thing up.
不如说我们配合得不错吧
Let's just say we make a good team.
敬我们
To us.
他进攻了  进攻了
There he goes. There he goes.
上啊  上啊  上啊
Come on, come on! Come on!
上啊  漂亮
Come on! Yeah!
从我记事起我就是这个样子了
I've been like this for as long as I can remember.
能给我举个例子吗
Can you give me an example?
在我很小的时候
Well, when I was little,
是拼写队的成员
I was in a spelling team at school
我真的很想赢
and I really wanted to win.
我也不知道为什么  也没有奖励
I don't know why. There was no prize.
没人在乎
No one cared.
我父母甚至都不知道我参加了
My parents didn't even know I was in it.
我只是觉得肩上有这样的责任
I just felt this weight on my shoulders,
就好像如果输了  我会  我也不知道
like if I lost, I'd...I don't know.
-我就是必须要赢  -那你赢了吗
- I just had to win. - And did you?
是的  你知道决胜的词是什么吗
Yep. Know what the winning word was?
责任
Responsibility.
你是那么想的吗
Is that what you feel?
一直有着需要赢的责任
A responsibility to win all the time?
永远要做最好的
To always be the best?
你可以这么说
That's one way to put it.
这种责任  从哪里来
And this responsibility -- where does it come from?
我也不知道  它就自然存在了
I'm not sure. It's just...there.
所以这是种内部压力
So it's an internal pressure.
算是吧
Kind of.
一旦你做得超过预期了
I mean, once you start overachieving,
人们就开始对你有所期待
people expect things from you.
人们是谁
Like what people?
就是  全世界
You know, the world...
老师  家长  其他孩子
Teachers, parents, other kids.
也不完全是内部的
It's not all internal.
别误会
Don't get me wrong.
我喜欢这种紧张的状态
I like the way I'm wired.
只有这样我才能上好学校
It's what's going to get me into a good school.
这才是我
It's what makes me who I am.
那感觉怎么样  做你自己
And how is that -- being who you are?
我不知道
I don't know.
大多数时候还不错
Mostly good.
有点累
A little exhausting.
有时候很艰难
Sometimes hard.
我觉得这就是你想要的答案吧
I guess there's your answer.
做我自己很难
It's hard being me.
再跟我说说你的家庭
Tell me a little more about your family.
就是个很普通的家庭
They're pretty normal, I guess.
我跟他们都不太一样
I'm not like any of them,
-但这对我没什么困扰  -从来没有吗
- But that doesn't really bother me. - Ever?
除非他们说"艾丽克斯  你太刻苦了"
Only when they say things like "Alex, you study too much"
或是"别紧张"  "去玩玩"之类的
or "Don't freak out" or "Go do something fun."
就是说你的兄弟姐妹
So, your siblings--
他们并没有你那样的压力
they don't experience the same pressures you do.
天呐  当然没有  他们才不在乎学业
Oh, god, no. They don't care about school.
你觉得原因是什么呢
Hmm. Why do you think that is?
你们都在同一屋檐下长大
I mean, you all grew up in the same house
有着同样的父母  而你却是唯一
with the same parents, yet you're the only one
为了达到高标准
who feels this enormous pressure
而感到巨大压力的人
to achieve at such a high level.
为什么要谈论我的家人
Why do we even have to talk about my family?
他们跟这事没关系
They don't have anything to do with this.
他们不懂我
They don't get me.
这种感觉如何
How's that feel?
-不知道  -你很聪明
- I don't know. - You're a smart girl.
-再好好想想  -我说了不知道
- Try a little harder. - I said I don't know.
我感觉
I feel...
有点孤单
kind of alone.
我知道孩子们都忙着准备入学考试
I realize our juniors are busy with SATs, so as a rule,
所以我每晚只布置两个小时的作业量
I only give two hours of homework a night.
-两个小时啊  -我们的学生非常棒
- Two hours? - Our students are highly advanced.
他们完全应付得来
It's nothing they can't handle.
我相信他们可以
You know, I'm-- I'm sure they can.
只是说他们要上两小时的课
It's just that if they have two hours in this class
还要上一小时的生物课
and they have an hour for A.P. Bio
还有一个半小时的文学课
and an hour and a half for, um, advanced lit
再加上  稍等
and-- hang on one second.
我要写在板子上
Let me just do this on the board,
两小时一小时再加一个半小时
'cause then it's-- um, we got 2 and 1 and 1.5
之后还有一个半小时
and then another, uh, hour and a half
历史课  算下来
for A.P. History-- gives us...
-六小时  -没错
- It's 6. - Yes!
妮娜  我就要算出来了
Nina, I was getting there.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you! Thank you so much!
要是你打字没那么大声
If I could just have a second to think
我就能静下心来计算了
without all the tippy-tappy typing.
六小时
6.
这下你们高兴了吧
Well, I hope you're happy.
你们毁了大家的躲避球赛
You've ruined dodgeball for everyone.
是她把球扔到我脸上的
She was the one who threw that ball in my face.
那是因为你色诱英格拉姆老师
Only because you threw yourself at Mr. Ingram.
拜托  女士们
Okay, ladies, please.
你们看不出你们在干什么吗
Can't you see what's going on here?
你们都只是想为孩子争取最好的机会
You both just want what's best for your kids.
我得帮韦斯利争取到这次旅行
I need to get this trip for Wesley.
我不想再看到他每次都对我生气
I'm tired of him being so mad at me all the time.
他为什么生气
Why is he mad?
他认为我和他爸离婚是我的错
Oh, he blames me for the divorce.
他爸爸总是那个好人
His father will always be the hero.
不在身边的人总是不会被责怪
It's hard to blame someone who's never there.
难道你不能理解吗
Now, can't you relate to that?
会好起来的
It will get better.
孩子们会明白谁是真正为他们好的
Kids always figure out who's really there for them.
对投影仪的事再次表示抱歉
Again, we're very sorry about the projector.
我周一会寄来支票
I'll send a check on Monday.
-亲爱的  -我惹事了
- Hi, honey. - I got in trouble.
她的事都记到我的帐上
Whatever she did, add it to my tab.
-好吧  来吧  -不不
- All right, let's do this. - No. No, no, no.
不是你俩  就你  来吧  警长
Not you two, just you. Come on, sheriff.
亲爱的  怎么样
Oh, hey, honey. How did it go?
挺好的  下周继续
Good. And I made another session for next week.
学校开放日怎么样
How was the open house?
非常紧张
Wow. So intense.
我都不知道你承受了那么大的压力
I had no idea the kind of pressure you're under.
亲爱的  我只在学校体验了两个小时
Honey, I was just you for two hours.
就已经快受不了了
I could barely hold it together.
你没有每天情绪失控真是太了不起了
I don't know how you don't have a meltdown every day.
-我  -亲爱的
- I... - Oh, honey.
宝贝  怎么了  是我说了什么吗
Sweetie, what? Did I say something?
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
没事
Okay.
乖
再次抱歉
Again, I am so sorry.
现在想来  我过来向你炫耀
I-I guess, in retrospect, it was a little crazy
我的州律师协会奖  实在有点疯狂
that I wanted to show you my state bar association award.
别说了
Stop.
可能是我太过激了
And it's possible I come on a little too strong.
不不不
No. No, no.
我以为我很环保
I like to think that I'm greener than I am,
但也许我只是想
but maybe I just want the credit
不像你那样卖力气就得到赞赏
without doing all the hard work that you do.
你说得对  是很不容易
Well, you're right-- it is hard,
但也会遭到孤立
but, you know, it's also alienating.
没人想跟我交朋友
You know, no one wants to be friends with me.
我都不记得上次请别人
I-I can't tell you the last time
来家里吃饭是什么时候了
I had people over for dinner,
也许这是好事
which is probably a good thing.
你知道太阳能嘛
You know, with solar power,
需要四天的时间才能烤熟一只鸡
it takes four days to roast a chicken.
-真的吗  -如果你想全熟的话
- Really? - If you want it cooked all the way through, yeah.
知道我得过三次沙门氏菌病吗
You know I had salmonella three times?
你可以来我家吃饭
If you want to come over to our house for dinner,
-我们欠你的  -你可以玩我的娃娃屋
- we kind of owe you. - You can play with my dollhouse.
真的吗
Yeah?
那是可持续材料做的吗
Does it made from sustainable materials?
当我没说
Forget it.